573.718.4588 john.gieselmann@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/johngieselmann johngieselmann.com

I pride myself in being an energetic people leader that loves pushing my team to build great things. I'm passionate about the user experience, love a good challenge and always make it a point to bring the fun with me.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MyFitnessPal

Following the sale of MyFitnessPal by Under Armour, my team played a critical role in the separation of backend services and data. After a successful divestiture, my time at MyFitnessPal has been focused on going where the problems need to be solved. I helped establish new backend engineering teams, transitioned to the web to focus on user experience, then moved into the improvement of our data and search quality. Now, my primary focus is leading a cross-functional team of engineers through new integrations within the Product Operating Model.

Sr. Engineering Manager | 08.2021 - Present

- Coaching and developing engineers to be collaborative, productive and autonomous teammates
- Collaborating with teammates on the delivery and execution of engineering efforts
- Partnered with leaders and other teams to develop data quality roadmaps and initiatives
- Planned and oversaw frontend engineering work for our web app, blog and internal tools
- Oversaw backend engineering efforts across all product teams with 20 direct & indirect reports

Engineering Manager | 01.2021 - 08.2021

- Led a remote team of 9 software engineers supporting backend services across all product verticals
- Coordinated engineering efforts for international and engineering empowerment product initiatives
- Facilitated cross-team efforts to migrate services away from Under Armour

Under Armour

I was the manager of one of the Foundational Services teams responsible for the unification of backend services implemented by all Under Armour businesses: MyFitnessPal, MapMyRun and Ecommerce. Our services included identity management, privacy compliance and the premium subscription service (my personal favorite).

Engineering Manager | 04.2020 - 12.2020

- Managed a team of 6 software engineers, providing feedback and guidance for growth
- Coordinated the adoption of our backend services and APIs by our mobile and web teams
- Supervised Salesforce Commerce Cloud integration with internal SSO and user profile service

Atmosphere

Following a successful Series A with S3 Ventures in 2019, I evolved CHIVE TV, a video streaming app, into a revenue generating, over-the-top (OTT) streaming service and SaaS platform for businesses known as Atmosphere.

Director of Engineering | 04.2019 - 03.2020

- Oversaw development of backend APIs and client applications across iOS, Android, tvOS, Roku and Web
- Architected and developed the application's business onboarding and subscription service
- Integrated video advertising supply-side platform and streaming analytics into the application
- Facilitated internal tools and application requirements for sales, marketing and accounting teams

Chive Media Group

My initial focus at Chive Media Group was the development of the CHIVE's social and community web platform before pivoting to sharing video content direct to consumers with OTT video streaming devices via the CHIVE TV application. CHIVE TV then became the primary product of Atmosphere after a successful Series A with S3 Ventures in 2019.

Director of Engineering | 01.2017 - 04.2019

- Led and coached an engineering, QA and sysadmin team of 12 in-house employees and remote contractors
- Orchestrated the transition of a video streaming app into a SaaS, digital signage platform
- Scoped, planned and coordinated engineering resources across multiple business properties

Senior Software Engineer | 01.2016 - 01.2017

- Helped drive architectural decisions across teams and provided technical review on projects
- Developed RESTful APIs to support high volume requests and scalable content delivery to mobile apps
- Integrated a subscription-based paywall across multiple company websites / properties

Software Engineer | 02.2015 - 01.2016

- Designed and developed a monolithic web platform for sharing user submitted photos
- Developed internal SSO across ecomm and primary website
- Integrated a gamification and cross-business rewards system for web and mobile platforms

People Productions

As a web developer, I built small and large scale web applications that spanned from frontend to backend. I helped spin out a custom sales management tool into its own platform as a startup product and company known as UpSync.

Lead Developer | 01.2013 - 02.2015

- Built and maintained web APIs and iOS features to scale up with expanded business needs
- Maintained servers, development environments and database administration

Web Developer | 08.2011 - 01.2013

- Developed frontend, data driven web applications for product pricing and cost analysis
- Built responsive, device-agnostic web apps and interactive presentations for product sales

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida

Bachelor of Arts, Digital Media | 05.2011

SKILLS

Languages PHP, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Java, Objective-C

Frameworks REST, Laravel, Zend, React, Vue, Angular, ¡Query, Node, Rails, Sass, WordPress

■ MySQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch

Infrastructure AWS, GCP, Vagrant, Docker, Kubernetes, Chef

Tools Vim, Git, Slack, Jira, Confluence, Adobe Suite, Stripe, Segment, DataDog, Postman